The next alpha factor that I'd like to share with you is based on the paper titled,
下面我要介绍的这个 alpha 因子与论文
Expected Skewness and Momentum.
《Expected Skewness AND Momentum》有关
Before we get into the formal definition of skewness,
在介绍偏态的正式定义之前
I'd like to give you a hypothetical example that hopefully will guide
先举个假设例子
your understanding as we discuss the conditional skewness and momentum vector.
帮助你理解条件偏态和动量因子
Why conditional? What word do you see in the title?
为何是条件因子？论文标题里有什么词？“AND”
"And", as a practitioner,
作为从业者
it's often helpful to think of the alpha factors in terms
从市场机制和/或行为心理学的角度
of market mechanics and or behavioral psychology.
思考alpha 因子经常很有帮助
If you look at which stocks are in the news,
如果你观察新闻里提到的股票
some stocks get more of press coverage and social media posts than others.
某些股票新闻报道更多 社交媒体曝光率更高
Let's hypothesize that stocks that tend to get higher than
假设媒体关注度高于平均值的股票
average media attention tend to also become overpriced.
往往被炒高
What might cause that mispricing?
什么可能会导致炒高？
When individual investors are flooded with news about a high flying company,
当散户遇到大量关于高曝光度公司的新闻时
there's a natural fear of missing out or "Fomo" as the kids are calling it these days.
很容易害怕错过 用流行语来说就是“社交控”
This sets up investors for a situation referred to as attentional bias.
这样就使投资者出现注意力偏差
Attentional bias is a phenomenon where people focus on some aspect at the expense of
注意力偏差是指人们只关注某个方面
focusing on the big picture and are more likely to
而忽略了全局状况
notice evidence that supports their prior existing beliefs.
更有可能注意到与既有观念一致的证据
So, when a stock that is getting lots of
当获得大量新闻报道的股票
news coverage has a high one day return in the past month,
在过去一个月具有很高的一日收益率时
this may trigger individual investors to
散户可能会觉得
see this as a sign that the stock will keep going up.
股票会继续上涨
Their fear of missing out may kick in,
他们担心错过机会
so they jump in and buy as well pushing the stock further up.
所以都买入股票 抬高了股价
Since this increase may not be based on fundamentals,
因为这种增长可能与基本面不符
the market as a whole both institutional investors and
所以整体市场（包括机构投资者和散户）
individual investors may realize that the stock is over bought and sell,
可能意识到股票被炒高了 所以又抛售
thus starting to push the stock price back down to earth.
促使股价回到正常水平
If this is indeed true,
如果的确是这种情况
then the maximum one day return in a historical window can be used as
那么历史窗口中的最大一日收益率
a reversal factor which can also be combined with
可以作为逆转因子
momentum to decide that the stock maybe over bought or oversold.
并且可与动量结合 判断股票是否炒高或卖超了
The maximum one day return over
我们可以根据一个月的一日收益率
a month is the way that we can measure skewness of returns.
衡量收益率的偏态
We'll explain skew in the next section.
我们将在下个部分解释偏态
Before we go to the next section though,
但是在继续转到下个部分之前
let's pause and talk generally about alpha factors again.
先暂停并再次大致讨论下 alpha 因子
Many of you might be skeptical of this approach as many newcomers to call financer.
很多人可能对这种方法表示怀疑 就像很多量化分析师新手一样
Surely in the context of this specific factor,
对于这个因子来说
you can think of a few occasions in recent memory where
你肯定能根据最近学到的知识
the idea behind this factor was wrong, maybe spectacularly wrong.
想到这种因子的理论有误（也许是大错特错）的情形
Meaning you can surely think of ideas where
你肯定能想到
a stock went up a lot and then continued going up.
股票上涨很多后继续上涨的情形
Alpha factors though are trying to capture a mispricing,
但是 Alpha 因子想要从以下几个方面
often imperceptible to humans across one,
发现人类通常觉察不到的错误定价信号
many stocks two, on a relative basis,
1. 很多股票 2. 相对而言
and three, persistent across time.
3. 在时间上持续下去
We are not trying to get very high conviction in any one specific stock.
我们并不想对任何一支股票非常确信
As we discussed in the section about the fundamental law of active management,
正如在主动管理基本定律部分讨论的
we can expect that our skill on any one stock will be low,
我们对一支股票的预测技能可能很差 这很正常
even imperceptibly difficult to distinguish from noise by a human.
甚至不易觉察地难以区分人类带来的噪点
Skill just has to be marginally better than 50-50 at the single trait level, and then,
在单个交易级别只需达到一半以上的准确率即可
we can apply it across many stocks to get
我们可以将信号应用到多支股票上
a complete alpha factor that hopefully exhibits good Sharpe ratio.
获得一个完整 alpha 因子并希望具有不错的夏普比率